Guide to the Marta Long presidential memorabilia collection, 1960-1981 MS2099
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Marta Long presidential memorabilia collection
1960-1981
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Long, Marta
MS2099
1 Linear Feet
Collection contains booklets, handbooks, invitations, programs and other ephemera relating to the activities of the Republican party. This material dates from 1960-81. The majority of the items are from the 1968 campaign to elect Richard M. Nixon and from the inauguration of Ronald Reagan in 1981. Of special note are party platforms from the Republican National Conventions of 1960, 1964, and 1968, as well as a book entitled "Nixon Speaks Out: Major Speeches and Statements" by Richard M. Nixon in the Presidential Campaign of 1968.
Box 1
Box 2
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Marta Long presidential memorabilia collection was donated to the Gelman Library in 1996. Ms
Historical or Biographical Note
Marta Long was a local political activist affiliated with the Republican party.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains booklets, handbooks, invitations, programs and other ephemera relating to the activities of the Republican party. This material dates from 1960-81. The majority of the items are from the 1968 campaign to elect Richard M. Nixon and from the inauguration of Ronald Reagan in 1981. Of special note are party platforms from the Republican National Conventions of 1960, 1964, and 1968, as well as a book entitled "Nixon Speaks Out: Major Speeches and Statements" by Richard M. Nixon in the Presidential Campaign of 1968. The latter contains speeches dealing with such topics as the Vietnam War, the American economy and the future of civil rights in America.
Civil rights; Inaugurations; Washington (D.C.); Political campaigns; Economic conditions; Vietnam war; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous); Long, Marta; Republican National Convention; Reagan, Ronald; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- )
- Republican Workers' Manual--Work and Win, 1960 -1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Republican Women's Leadership Manual, 1960 -1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Republican Platform 1960--Building a Better America (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Program--California's Salute to the President Lyndon B. Johnson, 07/19/1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Official Report of the Proceedings of the Twenty-eighth Republican National Convention, held in San Francisco, CA, 07/13/1964 -07/16/1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Rules adopted by Republican National Convention, held at San Francisco Hilton, 07/13/1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1964 Membership Directory, California Republican Democratic State Central Committees (Box 1, Folder 7)
- National Republican Workshops, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Northern California Committee to Elect President Johnson -- Campaign Materials, 1964 ca. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Salinger for Senator, San Francisco Headquarters, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Federal, State, and Local Responsibilities for Problems of Education: Task Force On the Function of Federal, State and Local Governments, 06/1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- The GOP Leader's Manual, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- A Call for New Fiscal Policies for the Government of the United States, 04/1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Campaign Handbook, Ways to Win, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Campaign Handbook, Contract for '68, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Republican National Committee Employee Rosters 1968 -- Summary of 1968 Election Outlook (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Nixon Speaks Out: Major Speeches and Statements by Richard M. Nixon in the Presidential Campaign of 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Schulz, Charles M., illustrator, The Peanuts Platform, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- The Chairman's Report for 1967 to the Republican National Committee, 01/23/1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Republican Platform 1968--We Must Think Anew and Act Anew, 08/06/1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- [Inaugural Committee?] "Staff Directory,", 12/09/1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Poster--"Nixon for President,", 1968 ca. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Newsletter--Facts and Issues, League of Women Voters of the United States 1969/70; Directory--United Citizens Committee; Directory--League of Women Voters 1970 National Convention, 1969 -1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 1977 Inaugural Guide to Washington: "A new spirit, a new commitment, a new America," (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Catalog -- Official Presidential Inaugural Commemoratives, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- [Gala Committee Notes] -- Presidential Inaugural Committee, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- [Gala Committee Notes] -- Presidential Inaugural Committee, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- [Gala Committee] Volunteer Job Descriptions -- Presidential Inaugural Committee, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- "Inaugural Activity Summary" -- Presidential Inaugural Committee, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Invitation to "Get Acquainted Party" -- Presidential Inaugural Committee, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Invitation to Inauguration of Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Invitation to Inauguration of Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- "Presidential Fact Sheet" -- Presidential Inaugural Committee, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Presidential Inaugural Committee -- 1981 Official Guide Book (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Program -- Inaugural Ball, Kennedy Center, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Program -- Inaugural Festivities at the Museums of the Smithsonian Institution, 01/16/1981 -01/20/1981 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Program -- 1981 Inaugural Gala, Capital Center (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Schedule of Events -- Presidential Inaugural Committee, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- "Thumbs Up America!" Inaugural Theme Song, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Telephone Directory -- Presidential Inaugural Committee, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Ticket stubs and volunteer passes, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Levine, Benjamin and Isabel F. Story. Statue of Liberty: National Monument, Liberty Island, NY, (reprint 1961), undated (Box 2, Folder 27)